webpackHotUpdate("static/development/pages/contradictions.js",{

/***/ "./constants/contradictions/genesis.js":
/*!*********************************************!*\
  !*** ./constants/contradictions/genesis.js ***!
  \*********************************************/
/*! exports provided: default */
/***/ (function(module, __webpack_exports__, __webpack_require__) {

"use strict";
__webpack_require__.r(__webpack_exports__);
var genesis = {
  book: "Genesis",
  answers: [{
    bookVerses: "1&ndash;2",
    question: "Do Genesis 1 and 2 present contradictory creation accounts?",
    allPassages: [{
      passage: "Genesis 1",
      text: ["11 And God said, \u201C<strong>Let the earth sprout vegetation, plants yielding seed, and fruit trees bearing fruit in which is their seed, each according to its kind, on the earth...</strong>\u201D 13 And there was evening and there was morning, the third day.", "24 And God said, \u201C<strong>Let the earth bring forth living creatures according to their kinds\u2014livestock and creeping things and beasts of the earth according to their kinds...</strong>\u201D", "26 Then God said, \u201C<strong>Let us make man in our image, after our likeness.</strong>\u201D"]
    }, {
      passage: "Genesis 2",
      text: ["5 <strong>When no bush of the field was yet in the land and no small plant of the field had yet sprung up\u2014for the Lord God had not caused it to rain on the land, and there was no man to work the ground</strong>, 6 and a mist was going up from the land and was watering the whole face of the ground\u2014 7 <strong>then the Lord God formed the man of dust from the ground and breathed into his nostrils the breath of life, and the man became a living creature</strong>. 8 And the Lord God planted a garden in Eden, in the east, and there he put the man whom he had formed. 9 <strong>And out of the ground the Lord God made to spring up every tree that is pleasant to the sight and good for food</strong>. The tree of life was in the midst of the garden, and the tree of the knowledge of good and evil...", "18 Then the Lord God said, \u201CIt is not good that the man should be alone; I will make him a helper fit for him.\u201D 19 <strong>Now out of the ground the Lord God had formed every beast of the field and every bird of the heavens</strong> and brought them to the man to see what he would call them."]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "1:26",
    question: "Are there one or many Gods?",
    quickAnswer: '<p>The doctrine of the Trinity teaches that there is one God who exists in three persons. "God" and "person" are not the same thing, so there is no contradiction. The plural pronouns in Genesis could either be referring to the Trinity, or they could be a "royal we," which is sometimes used for monarchs.</p>',
    fullPost: "/answers/are-there-one-many-gods",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "There is one God",
      passages: [{
        passage: "Deuteronomy 6:4",
        text: "4 â€œHear, O Israel: The Lord our God, the Lord is one"
      }, {
        passage: "Isaiah 43:10",
        text: "10 \u201CYou are my witnesses,\u201D declares the Lord, \u201Cand my servant whom I have chosen, that you may know and believe me and understand that I am he. Before me no god was formed, nor shall there be any after me."
      }, {
        passage: "Isaiah 44:6",
        text: "6 Thus says the Lord, the King of Israel and his Redeemer, the Lord of hosts: \u201CI am the first and I am the last; besides me there is no god."
      }, {
        passage: "Isaiah 44:8",
        text: "8 Fear not, nor be afraid; have I not told you from of old and declared it? And you are my witnesses! Is there a God besides me? There is no Rock; I know not any.\u201D"
      }]
    }, {
      heading: "There are many Gods",
      passages: [{
        passage: "Genesis 1:26",
        text: "26 Then God said, \u201CLet us make man in our image, after our likeness. And let them have dominion over the fish of the sea and over the birds of the heavens and over the livestock and over all the earth and over every creeping thing that creeps on the earth.\u201D"
      }, {
        passage: "Genesis 3:22",
        text: "22 Then the Lord God said, \u201CBehold, the man has become like one of us in knowing good and evil. Now, lest he reach out his hand and take also of the tree of life and eat, and live forever\u2014\u201D"
      }, {
        passage: "Genesis 11:7",
        text: "7 Come, let us go down and there confuse their language, so that they may not understand one another's speech.\u201D"
      }, {
        passage: "1 Corinthians 8:5",
        text: "5 For although there may be so-called gods in heaven or on earth\u2014as indeed there are many \u201Cgods\u201D and many \u201Clords\u201D\u2014"
      }, {
        passage: "1 John 5:8",
        text: "8 the Spirit and the water and the blood; and these three agree."
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "3:9",
    question: "Does God asking Adam, \"Where are you?\", mean that God doesn't know everything?",
    quickAnswer: "<p>God simply asked a question that He already knew the answer to. This is often done to teach something. So, God asking adam, \"Where are you,\" does not mean that God is not omniscient.</p>",
    fullPost: "/answers/genesis-3-9-gods-omniscience",
    allPassages: [{
      passage: "Genesis 3:9",
      text: "9 But the Lord God called to the man and said to him, \u201CWhere are you?\u201D"
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "3:16",
    question: "Was it wrong for God to multiply the pain of women in childbearing?",
    quickAnswer: "<ol>\n      <li>Adam and Eve sinned, and one consequence of sin is pain.</li>\n      <li>Adam, as the \"head\" of all mankind, represented the entire human race in his sin. This is the doctrine of original sin.</li>\n      <li>We have no grounds upon which to call the doctrine of original sin unfair.</li>\n    </ol>",
    fullPost: "/answers/genesis-3-16-pain-women-child-bearing",
    allPassages: [{
      passage: "Genesis 3:16",
      text: "16 To the woman he said, \u201CI will surely multiply your pain in childbearing; in pain you shall bring forth children. Your desire shall be contrary to[a] your husband, but he shall rule over you.\u201D"
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "3:22",
    see: ["genesis", "1:26"]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "4:17",
    question: "Where did Cain get his wife?",
    quickAnswer: "<p>Cain's wife was one of his sisters. God did not prohibit sexual relations with one's close relative until Leviticus 18:6. One purpose of incest laws was to protect people from birth defects, but Cain lived during an early time when the genetic pool was still very pure.</p>",
    fullPost: "/answers/genesis-4-17-cain-wife",
    allPassages: [{
      passage: "Genesis 4:16-17",
      text: "Then Cain went away from the presence of the Lord and settled in the land of Nod, east of Eden. Cain knew his wife, and she conceived and bore Enoch. When he built a city, he called the name of the city after the name of his son, Enoch."
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "5:1-31",
    question: "Did people live hundreds of years in Genesis?",
    quickAnswer: "<p>Adam, as the first human created and as one created without sin, likely had such an uncorrupted body and genetic constitution that he, and his descendants after him for some time, was able to live hundreds of years.</p>",
    fullPost: "/answers/did-people-live-hundreds-years-genesis-5",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "",
      passages: [{
        passage: "",
        text: ""
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "5:24",
    question: "Did anyone ascend to heaven before Jesus?",
    quickAnswer: "<p>The \"heaven\" that Enoch and Elijah were taken up into is different from the \"heaven\" that Jesus ascended to. Believers will not experience the fullness of heaven until Jesus returns and they receive a resurrected body.</p>",
    fullPost: "/answers/did-anyone-ascend-heaven-before-jesus",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "Enoch and Elijah ascended to heaven",
      passages: [{
        passage: "Genesis 5:24",
        text: "Enoch walked with God, and he was not,[a] for God took him."
      }, {
        passage: "2 Kings 2:11",
        text: "And as they still went on and talked, behold, chariots of fire and horses of fire separated the two of them. And Elijah went up by a whirlwind into heaven."
      }, {
        passage: "Hebrews 11:5",
        text: "By faith Enoch was taken up so that he should not see death, and he was not found, because God had taken him. Now before he was taken he was commended as having pleased God."
      }]
    }, {
      heading: "Only Jesus has ascended to heaven",
      passages: [{
        passage: "John 3:13",
        text: "No one has ascended into heaven except he who descended from heaven, the Son of Man."
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "6:2-5",
    question: "Who were the \"sons of God\" in Genesis 6?",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "",
      passages: [{
        passage: "",
        text: ""
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "6:6-7",
    question: "Does God change His mind?",
    quickAnswer: "<p>No. When it appears that God is changing His mind in the Bible, the Bible is utilizing anthropomorphism, or the attribution of human traits, emotions, or intentions to non-human entities. This is done to help explain God in language we can more easily understand.</p>",
    fullPost: "/answers/does-god-change-his-mind",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "God does not change",
      passages: [{
        passage: "Malachi 3:6",
        text: "For I the Lord do not change; therefore you, O children of Jacob, are not consumed."
      }]
    }, {
      heading: "God changes His mind",
      passages: [{
        passage: "Genesis 6:6-7",
        text: "And the Lord regretted that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart. So the Lord said, \"I will blot out man whom I have created from the face of the land, man and animals and creeping things and birds of the heavens, for I am sorry that I have made them.\""
      }, {
        passage: "Exodus 32:14",
        text: "And the Lord relented from the disaster that he had spoken of bringing on his people."
      }, {
        passage: "Jonah 3:10",
        text: "When God saw what they did, how they turned from their evil way, God relented of the disaster that he had said he would do to them, and he did not do it."
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "6:19-20",
    question: "How many of each kind did Noah bring into the ark, two, seven, or fourteen?",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "",
      passages: [{
        passage: "",
        text: ""
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "7:1",
    question: "Is anyone righteous/blameless, or have all sinned?",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "",
      passages: [{
        passage: "",
        text: ""
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "7:2-3",
    see: ["genesis", "6:19-20"]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "11:8-9",
    question: "If God is not the author of confusion, then what about the Tower of Babel?",
    quickAnswer: "<p>The two passages are completely different contexts. 1 Corinthians 14:33 is referring to God not being the author of confusion in terms of order within the church, and Genesis 11:7-9 is about God creating confusion as judgment for the people's pride and sin. The phrase \"author of confusion\" in 1 Corinthians 14:33 is restricted to a particular context that does not apply to Genesis 11:7-9.</p>",
    fullPost: "/answers/god-author-confusion-babel",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "God is not the author of confusion",
      passages: [{
        passage: "1 Corinthians 14:33",
        text: "For God is not a God of confusion but of peace..."
      }]
    }, {
      heading: "God creates confusion at the Tower of Babel",
      passages: [{
        passage: "Genesis 11:7-9",
        text: "\"Come, let us go down and there confuse their language, so that they may not understand one another's speech.\" So the Lord dispersed them from there over the face of all the earth, and they left off building the city. Therefore its name was called Babel, because there the Lord confused the language of all the earth. And from there the Lord dispersed them over the face of all the earth."
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "17:1",
    question: "Has anyone seen God?",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "",
      passages: [{
        passage: "",
        text: ""
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "18:1",
    see: ["genesis", "17:1"]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "19:8",
    question: "Was Lot righteous? Wasn't it wrong for Lot to give his daughters to the crowd of men?",
    quickAnswer: "<p>There is no contradiction because two things can be true at the same time: 1) Lot sinned in giving his daughters to the crowd of men (Genesis 19:8), and 2) generally speaking, Lot was overall a righteous man (2 Peter 2:7).</p>",
    fullPost: "/answers/was-lot-righteous-gave-daughters-to-crowd-men",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "Lot gives his daughters to the crowd of men",
      passages: [{
        passage: "Genesis 19:8",
        text: "Behold, I have two daughters who have not known any man. Let me bring them out to you, and do to them as you please. Only do nothing to these men, for they have come under the shelter of my roof."
      }]
    }, {
      heading: "Lot is righteous",
      passages: [{
        passage: "2 Peter 2:7",
        text: "...and if he rescued righteous Lot, greatly distressed by the sensual conduct of the wicked..."
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "22:1",
    question: "Does God tempt people?",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "",
      passages: [{
        passage: "",
        text: ""
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "22:1-2",
    question: "Was it wrong for God to command Abraham to kill his son Isaac?",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "",
      passages: [{
        passage: "",
        text: ""
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "22:2",
    question: "Did Abraham have one son or two sons?",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "",
      passages: [{
        passage: "",
        text: ""
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "37:28",
    question: "Who sold Joseph, the Midianites or the Ishmaelites?",
    quickAnswer: "<p>In these passages, Ishmaelites and Midianites are referring to the same group of people, so there is no contradiction.</p>",
    fullPost: "/answers/who-bought-joseph-ishmaelites-midianites",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "The Ishmaelites bought Joseph",
      passages: [{
        passage: "Genesis 37:28",
        text: "Then Midianite traders passed by. And they drew Joseph up and lifted him out of the pit, and sold him to the Ishmaelites for twenty shekels of silver. They took Joseph to Egypt."
      }, {
        passage: "Genesis 39:1",
        text: "Now Joseph had been brought down to Egypt, and Potiphar, an officer of Pharaoh, the captain of the guard, an Egyptian, had bought him from the Ishmaelites who had brought him down there."
      }]
    }, {
      heading: "The Midianites bought Joseph",
      passages: [{
        passage: "Genesis 37:36",
        text: "Meanwhile the Midianites had sold him in Egypt to Potiphar, an officer of Pharaoh, the captain of the guard."
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "37:36",
    see: ["genesis", "37:28"]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "38:9",
    question: "Was it wrong for God to kill a man for \"wasting [his] semen on the ground\"?",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "",
      passages: [{
        passage: "",
        text: ""
      }]
    }]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "39:1",
    see: ["genesis", "37:28"]
  }, {
    bookVerses: "47:31",
    question: "Did Jacob worship at the head of the bed or leaning on a staff?",
    allPassages: [{
      heading: "",
      passages: [{
        passage: "",
        text: ""
      }]
    }]
  }]
};
/* harmony default export */ __webpack_exports__["default"] = (genesis);

/***/ })

})
//# sourceMappingURL=contradictions.js.1df051466886224c2247.hot-update.js.map